We're going to call to order this regular meeting of the Miami Special Utility Authority for today's date.
I'm too on the agenda's invocation by the pastor of Southern Hills Baptist Church.
Herb Young.
I hope thanks for being here.
Let's go to the Lord and prayer.
I Father and I God, we are so grateful for all that we live in this country, God, and in this great state.
Father, we thank you for our representatives, God, the runs who serve us so faithfully.
I pray, God, that you forgive us for the problems we should solve ourselves that we dump on them instead.
And God will pray for their guidance and for their wisdom, God, in understanding the other issues before them and before this town, God guide them.
Give them to direction and discretion and God give them your wisdom.
Father, we pray, though that we'll be faithful to love you with all our heart, mind, and soul and strength.
And love our neighbors as ourself.
We pray and ask your blessings upon this town.
In Jesus name we pray.
Amen.
Please go on in the pledge.
I believe that the Lord of the United States of America and do it about that work for which it stands.
One nation, on the God, in the name of the Lord, in the name of the Lord, in the name of the Lord.
I don't fear as public input, unscheduled personal parents.
For anyone in the audience that wishes to address the authority on any of the agenda items.
Being none, I don't find as a consent agenda, staff recommends item 6 and 7 for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions, I'll entertain a motion.
May I make a motion to provide them 6 and 7 in the consent agenda?
And a second please?
Yes, I'll vote.
Vote all.
Johnson?
Aye.
Lewis?
I have a set in World of Financial Services engagement letter to perform a 2016 electric water and wastewater rate study.
GL and Tyler.
So in your packet is the letter engagement with Will Dan Financial Services.
It's formally known as economists.com that's who have used since 2009.
It's to do a rate study on our electric water and wastewater.
Last year, they did just a study on electric rates and staff.
It was based on a five year plan.
Staff brought to you a request to only approve the first year's first year's recommendation.
You all are the council did by ordinance and then staff said that they would bring back an updated study this year.
And that's what we're trying to do here.
It has been seven years since the water and wastewater rates have been studied.
We do have it scheduled until 2019 to raise the water and wastewater rates.
It's just on schedule since 2009.
But staff is recommending that we include that in the rate study.
We think it's just prudent to do that.
So this will give us a sink on all three, which was one of the questions of why we did electric by itself.
And then we're coming back and doing the other.
So we'll get, we'll get in sync on this and then going forward,
anticipate five year cycle or whatever we do all three.
Okay.
Any questions?
I'll make a motion.
to approve well-infinancial services engagement letter to perform the 2016
electric water, a wastewater and electric study. Do we have a second?
Well, second. Roll call, please.
Shills. Aye. Johnson. Aye.
Lower your eye.
I'm not an ultimate associates engineering agreement.
Dean, your honor. I wrote a fairly long explanation about this.
I'm not going to go into it in great detail.
But I will explain that as you know we do have and they can see right now in our
city engineering position. In lieu of filling a city engineer position and looking at this,
what is going on right now in Miami, we have a lot of different projects that are taking
place that probably are too much for one person, but we're not a large enough organization
to bring on board two or three engineers to have on staff.
So in essence what I'm suggesting is at this point that we farm out our engineering services
to also an associates for a period of time. Now we do have two deliverables that are part
of this agreement. One of them is to have a road study and a maintenance study taken care of by
October 31st by the end of October. The second which will be a follow-up will be on our utilities,
our electric water, and sewer. I mentioned Tyler in my report that he's been doing quite a bit of work
looking at our utilities. I know everybody recognizes the pot holes and has problems with those,
but we have just as much trouble with some of our other utilities as well and we're needing to get a
good project like that involved as well. Both Ron Merch and Jack Schaler, who are the two people
that are going to be the principles, Ron is indicated when I introduced him as a former city manager.
We knew each other when we were serving in Missouri. Jack is formerly with the city of
jobs and its public works and public works department there, so they have not only the engineering
knowledge, but also the knowledge about how a city operates to be able to get us the type of work that we need.
Along that line, there will also be working with our firm on the rate study because obviously we
not only the rates to cover our costs but to cover our maintenance as well. And also to do some
other projects with us to make sure that I think Christy was the one that said we kind of have an
organizational memory or try to develop an organizational memory that utilities and streets are
working and arm in need together. We quick projects that are coming up, we need to fix the pavement
at first street and main right in front of the Coleman. The pavement's not in very good shape right there.
We did do the micro surface which helped that in the intersection itself. We still have problems with
not only the pavement but also the drainage and we need to engineer new islands to be able to take
that stop sign out of the middle of the intersection and bring it up to speed like we did at main
and central. So they can help us with projects like this. We've had some people that are recently
complained and I know Tyler is working on some projects related to some of our water.
systems, where people are still having either cloudy water or rust in their water and we need
to upgrade that and they can help us with the engineering as we do the projects.
And even even recognize we had a letter to the editor in the newspaper about concerns
about potholes, especially C Street, which was identified as a significant problem.
And what I hope Jack and Ron and Elson can do is help us stretch our dollars as much as
we can so that the money we spend on streets, we're doing it in a good manner and a
positive manner, but try to get as much work as we possibly can.
We're just wrapping up about 1.8 million in our last fiscal year, we have 2.5 million
this year.
I hope that the projects that we'll re-bring you to you and the nautidists and
future will have a lot of citizen input as to what we need to do, but just try to have a
different way of looking at our streets and trying to get a little more nimble in how we react
to some of our projects.
That's why I'm lying on the intersection there at the call.
I'm hoping we'll have it done this season.
We really need to get on that very quickly, not just because of the asphalt, which is deteriorating,
but also we have the chronic flooding.
We're having to put sandbags in front of the lobby of the Coleman and front of the CBB.
They can help us with the engineering to eliminate that, so Shannon doesn't have to get sandbags
at every time it rains.
And does that include moving the stop sign?
Yes.
I'm hoping it'll be this at the end of the summer and in Paul.
Exactly.
Probably in an overlay, but this is why we need to help bring them on board as to not only give us the best way
to take care of it, but also the design that would go into it and probably even let it out for
beds if we have an outside contractor help us with it.
And where in the budget are we getting a funding for this degree?
We're using the funding that we would have had for the engineer's position.
The engineer position when you add salary and benefits was on 133,000.
This agreement is for 200 hours, which includes the deliverables I was talking about for 120,000.
But again with Olson, the depth of their knowledge because they can bring in specialties.
I think when that 200 hours will probably get as much as we would, out of a single employee for 2,000 hours.
You don't that can be over 200 hours?
I don't think this engagement would be over 200.
But we could have separate engagements.
For example, in the future, Neil, you and I talked about West Central.
And we need to take a good look at West Central and how we need to take care of the asphalt on that.
One of the problems with West Central, though, is we have old water and sewer lines that run along there.
And if we take care of the asphalt, we might have a problem with the water lines.
So one thing that we would have Olson help us with is not only look at the asphalt, but look at whatever we would have to do in utilities.
And make sure that we don't pay for straightening and have to do it.
get out again because we have waterline breaks. So they would help us with that but that would
be under a separate contract because but if we ever did a project like that anyway we would
be hiring an engineering firm. So those would be separate contracts. So this contract and just kind
of getting it started getting our water and sewer system in place the kind of the kind of the
capital plans that are compliance that we need to have done. That engagements about 120. It could
expand but any of those agreements would be coming to you for approval. We have representatives here
from Olsen if you wanted to ask them any questions or I didn't like that they came all the way from
Joplin. Why don't we go away from Springfields though. Now we appreciate you guys coming. I know you
have a history with Dean and if he has confidence in you then we have confidence in you. We appreciate
the opportunity. We are pretty excited about that. You know, I'll try to move my amount along with doing
things in an coordinated manner, which is a really important aspect. So the coordination is Dean mentioned
a very vital on street projects. What's above the ground is a minor part of what we're going to be looking
at because which don't say underground is as big or as you probably believe in it. So what you said
is that they have a street and they have to dig it out here so you didn't take the consideration
what's underground. Exactly. Exactly. And I've soon ended right work in the Springfield area in the
Joplin area and glad you're bringing it. And by the way Olsen and Associates he's also the firm that did
the engineering for the demolition of the Eagle picture building on BJ tunnel Avenue. So they're familiar
with that project as well. But they did that for the state of Oklahoma. Well that's a thing for the
opportunity. Thank you. So do we have a motion to approve? I'll make a motion that we approve
the agreement with those to the Associates. And the second roll call please? Lewis. Hi. Johnson. All right.
Sure. Hi. Item 10 of the new business. Dean or Dean of the Trustees and the new business.
Not for me. Item 11 staff reports are in your packet. The staff is available for any questions.
If there are none. Item 12 is community announcements. And 13 is executive session.
For some of it to 25 of OS 307 B4 for the initial communications with the trust attorney.
And also pursuant to sections 25 of OS 307. He and section 305. Do we have a motion to go on executive
session for the reasons listed on agenda item 13. What do you do, you're on? Yes. It can be my
recommendation that public disclosure of the conversation we're about to have. Seriously,
and community of this body to process the point. Thank you. And and welcome to be
getting his feet wet. The last meeting we had a special meeting and David is
resigning his office effective August 31 and moving on to other pastures.
Greener or otherwise he's not sure yet. And I had been his agreed to serve as
interim and we have a range for about a month and a half overlap. So we got
double protection and I we think. Anyway, anyway, thank you's been for
putting that out and adding that to the record. So with that said, do we have a
motion to go on the exact same. You're doing my commotion to go on the exact same.
And a second roll call please. Johnson, Lewis, hi,
show us. Hi.
So, yes you do. Okay, we are back item 14 is direction to trust attorney,
considering our concerning true server logistics. Do we have a motion to direct
or legal counsel to settle that suit per the offer made?
Yeah, I'm like that motion. And a second please.
Second roll call. Johnson.
Got it. Lewis, hi, show us. Hi. I'm 15 adjourned. I don't make the motion to adjourn. Do we have a second?
I'm 15. I'm a second.
Soaps. Hi. Lewis, hi. Johnson.
We are done.